Alright, so we have it so that it looks like
the player is running through the scene.
What in fact, everything is
actually just flying out the player.
So now what we're going
to do is we're actually
going to use a spawn
manager to be able
to create more obstacles
that fly at the player.
So to do that, we're going
to go into our hierarchy
and we can just right-click
and create empty.
Now we have an empty game object
and this will be our spawn manager.
And then in our scripts, we're going
to make a spawn manager script.
And then just make sure to click
and drag that onto our spawn manager.
So now that we know it's
been added as a component.
So we'll open our spawn manager up.
So in our script, we're going to
need a reference to our obstacle.
So we need to make it public so that
we can drop that reference in there.
And since it's a prefab, we
have to use a game object.
And then we'll just call
this obstacle prefab for now.
And then close that.
Now we're going to
create another variable,
very similar to a variable
that we made before.
So this will be private, so we can just
set it whenever we want inside of our code.
It'll be a vector three
because we're doing a position.
And this will be the spawn
position for our obstacles.
And we'll set this to be a new vector
three since we're getting another position.
And we'll set it to, let's
call it 25 on the X so
that it's all the way on
the right side of the screen.
We don't need it in the
air, so zero on the Y.
And then we don't need any kind of depth
towards us, so we'll call it zero on the Z.
And then in our start
method, we're going to create
that prefab once again
using our instantiate method.
So this way we can create clones
or copies of our obstacle prefab.
The object that we're going to create is
our obstacle prefab, which we listed above.
We're going to have it spawn at
the position that we set in our variable.
And we want it to be
facing the same direction
that we set it when
we created this prefab.
So get the obstacle prefab.
We're going to get its transform component
and we'll get the rotation of our prefab.
So you can see back in
unity in our spawn manager
script, it's updated to have
that instantiate method.
It's got our variables.
So now when we
press play, our obstacle
should fly at us and we
should create another one.
And when we see one obstacle
interesting, so at the bottom
here it says that there was an
unassigned reference exception.
So this red exclamation point
means that it was an error.
And it says that our obstacle prefab wasn't
assigned obstacle prefab of spawn manager.
So I think actually what happened
in our spawn manager, I see.
So I didn't actually drag the
obstacle prefab into the variable.
So let me do that really quick, cool.
So now when I press
play, now up there you go.
So we have two.
And I wonder if two are just going to fly
at us randomly from the screen, perfect.
So since we're spawning
one of our obstacles
through code, we
don't actually really need
this obstacle anymore, that's just
about everything it's going to do.
And we're not editing a massive amount.
So we'll just remove that.
So in that way, when we press play,
it spawns one and it flies at us, cool.
So now what you're
going to do is create your
own empty game object in your
project hierarchy, call it spawn manager.
And then in your scripts, you're
going to make a spawn manager script.
You're going to add that as a component to
the spawn manager game object in our scene.
And then in our spawn
manager script, you're
going to make a variable to get
the reference of our obstacle prefab.
So it'll be public.
So that way we can
actually attach a prefab to it.
It'll be a game object since it's a prefab.
We're going to make a private position
that we're going to spawn things at.
So we're going to use the
coordinates 25, 0 and 0.
And then we're going
to instantiate a new
obstacle prefab at our
spawn position and make
sure that it spawns at the rotation
that we had the prefab set up before.
And then last but not least, don't do what
I did and make sure to drag your obstacle
prefab into the obstacle prefab section
here in your spawn manager script.
Now it's your turn.